《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on "The Flash"...
原来你一直藏在这里
So this is where you've been hiding.
我认为你害怕使用自己的超能力
I think you're afraid to use your powers
因为你认为自己会变成某个你恨的人
because you think you'll become like someone you hate.
我知道你在为了我们这么做
I know you're doing it for all of us.
这就是做英雄的意义
That's what it means to be a hero.
我知道我选了对的人
I knew I picked the right guy.
-他要死了  -冰霜  我们怎么救他
- He's gonna die. - Frost, how do we save him?
我不知道  我挽救不了这种情况
I don't know! I can't fix this.
接受拉姆齐的血
Accepting Ramsey's blood
能拯救你的身体  但无法拯救你的灵魂
would save your body but not your soul.
你会失去你最好的一面
You would lose the best of you.
爱瑞丝所爱的那部分
The part of you that Iris loves.
那不是巴里
That's not Barry.
巴里
Barry.
整个世界将会见识到
The entire world will embrace
血怒
Bloodwork!
你们还好吗
Are you guys okay?
还好
Yeah.
我不理解  那不是巴里
I don't understand. That wasn't Barry.
那就是他
Yeah, it was.
拉姆齐把他变成了他的血亲
Ramsey turned him into one of his Blood Brothers.
巴贝尔协议启动
Babel Protocols initiated.
巴贝尔协议是怎么回事
What's Babel Protocols?
我以为那只是你加在巴里战衣里的
I thought that was just some defense stuff
某种防御机制
that you added to Barry's suit.
那是初代协议
That was version one.
第二代协议在尖端实验室周围开启防护力场
Version 2.0 puts up a force field around S.T.A.R. Labs.
任何事物都无法进出
Nothing gets in, nothing goes out--
连我们的通讯信号都不行
not even our comms.
我建这个是为了
I built them just in case...
以防闪电侠黑化
just in case the Flash ever went dark.
巴里说拉姆齐让他做出选择
Barry said that Ramsey gave him a choice.
为什么他会选择变成这样
Why--why would he choose this?
也许他决定选择永生
Maybe he decided eternal life was better
而不是在危机中死去
than dying in Crisis.
拉姆齐在利用巴里
Ramsey's using Barry.
不管在他让巴里做什么  拉姆齐早已谋划好
And whatever he's having him do, he's got a plan.
闪 电 侠
第六季
第八集
你在搜索警用通讯频道吗
You have a police scanner?
因为这东西是通过模拟信号传输的
I'm hoping that since this thing transmits in analog,
我本希望能搞清楚
we can figure out what's going on
尖端实验室外面发生了什么
outside S.T.A.R. Labs.
我搞不懂
I don't get it.
拉姆齐为什么不让巴里醒来后
Why didn't Ramsey just have Barry kill us
就立马杀掉我们
as soon as he woke up?
我不知道  不过先别以为巴里不会杀我们
I don't know, but don't count us out yet,
还记得我在研究的那项技术吗
You know that tech I've been working on?
光子发射器
Meet the Photon Emitter.
怎么  你造了一把射线枪
So what, you built a ray gun?
这不是一把射线枪
It's not a ray gun,
这是一把能够发射百万剂量光子辐射的武器
it's a weapon that can deliver megadoses of photon radiation--
是和癌症病人所受的放射性治疗
the same kind of radiation
同样的辐射
typically administered to cancer patients.
它到底有什么用
What exactly does it do?
我的理论是  这些光子应该足够强
My theory is that these photons could be strong enough
可以摧毁拉姆齐的意识感染
to destroy Ramsey's sentient infection.
如果我离他足够近去轰炸他
If I get close enough to blast him,
他应该能变回人类的形态
he should revert back to his human form.
那样他仍有噬血细胞综合症
He'd still have HLH,
但至少不再会是一个黏糊糊的丧尸之王了
but at least he wouldn't be a gooey zombie overlord anymore.
那其他被感染的人呢
What about everyone else that was infected?
他们也会被治愈吗
Would they be cured?
是的  他们会摆脱粘液
Yes. They'd lose the goo,
恢复到正常状态
they'd go back to normal.
但由于拉姆齐是唯一一个
But since Ramsey's the only one
可以制造更多血亲兄弟的人
that can create more Blood Brothers,
我建议我们先攻击他
I say we hit at him first.
然后攻击黑暗闪电侠
Then Dark Flash.
你测试过了吗
And you've tested this?
我都还没完全做好它
Well, I haven't even finished building it,
所以没有  我还没测试过
so no, no I haven't tested it.
那你的意思是
So let me get this straight.
你要用一种极度强大的还未测试过的设备
You wanna shoot radiation at my husband
朝我的丈夫发射辐射吗
out of some crazy powerful device that you've never tested?
爱瑞丝  这是我们现在唯一的办法了
Iris, this is the only plan we have.
这可能会杀死巴里  西斯科
This could kill Barry, Cisco.
有人吗  救救我
Anyone there? Please help me.
这座城市被占领了
The city's being overrun.
我正在用一位警察的无线通话器
I'm using a police officer's radio.
他正在变成某种怪物
He's turning into some kind of monster.
他的眼睛都黑了
His eyes are black.
拉姆齐在扩散他的感染
Ramsey's spreading his infection.
那正是他断掉全城通讯的时候
That's where he took down communication citywide.
凯特琳曾经说过  拉姆齐的感染样本显示
Caitlin once said Ramsey's infection sample
他需要受害者在遭到他的袭击前
indicate he needs his victims to be afraid
处于惊恐的状态
before he attacks them.
你的网络好用吗
Hey, is your Internet working?
停电了吗
What's with the lights?
我不知道
I don't know.
那是谁
Who's that?
进来  进来
Get inside, get inside.
他好像得了狂犬病之类的
He looks like he has rabies or something.
是米切·罗密欧  你还记不记得
Mitch Romero-- you remember the mobster
那个被拉姆齐变成血亲们的歹徒
that Ramsey turned into a Blood Brother?
乔说他就是这副样子
Well, Joe said that he looked just like that.
过来
Come here.
我们要怎么做
What-- what do we do?
我们要离开这栋楼
We gotta get out of this building.
记住  这些人是无辜的
Remember, these people are innocent!
只能采取非致命攻击
Nonlethal force only!
你的努力都白费了  队长
Your efforts are in vain, Captain.
我要在黎明前转变这座城市
I'm going to transform this city by dawn,
而你阻止不了我
and you can't stop me.
住手  罗素医生
Stand down, Dr. Rosso.
罗素是我的人类名字  他有人类计划
Rosso's my human name, and he had human plans.
但我现在叫血怒  我并不是一个人
My name is Bloodwork now, and I am not alone.
闪电侠  你不是这样的
Flash, this isn't you.
不管你出了什么事  我们都可以治好
Whatever happened to you, we will fix it.
需要治好的是人性
It's humanity that needs fixing.
你为什么让这种事发生
Why would you let that happen?
因为他已经不是巴里了
'Cause this isn't Barry anymore.
拉姆齐  不管你有什么计划
Ramsey, whatever the hell your plan is,
我们都会阻止你的
we will stop you.
我已经完成了
I've already done it.
我已经治愈了死亡
I've cured death...
但你们不能享有
but not for you.
继续我们的任务
Continue our mission.
杀了他们
Kill them.
我来找你了
I'm coming for you.
你寻求真相
You seek the truth.
诺武
Novu.
如果你希望知道所有的事
If you wish to know all,
让我们看到你的忠诚  一切将会揭示
show your allegiance and all will be revealed.
听起来不错  等一下
Yeah, that sounds great. Oh, wait.
不  我不跟伪神做交易
No, I don't barter with false gods!
臣服于我  你渴望的一切都将属于你
Bow down to me and all you desire shall be yours.
让我进去
Let me in.
Let me in!
臣服于我
Bow down to me!
经过一个又一个星球
Planet after planet...
一个又一个地球才找你  诺武
Earth after Earth I've tracked you, Novu,
你以为耍一些卑鄙的心理游戏
and you think some paltry mind games
和一面小石墙就能阻挡我
and a little rock wall is gonna stop me.
那你就大错特错了
You've got another think coming.
我会找到你的
I'm coming for you.
你阻止不了我
And you can't stop me!
又怎么了
What's this now?
愤怒之神的惩罚
Punishment from an angry god...
还是说线路有问题
or simply faulty wiring?
我说  赐予我们一点光明吧
I say, let there be light.
还是没有信号
Still nothing.
姑娘  我们可以的
Hey, girl. We got this.
我们只要达到走廊尽头
We just need to get to the end of the hallway
进到楼梯间就行了
and into the stairwell.
对不起
I'm sorry.
很对不起  我做不到
I'm so sorry. I can't.
我连动都动不了
I can't even move.
怎么了
What's wrong?
恐惧
Fear.
有太多的恐惧  我可以感觉得到
There's so much fear, and I can feel it,
楼里肯定还有其他人
and I think there must be other people in the building.
这地方是空的
The place is empty.
这么晚没人工作了
No one else is working this late.
-到处都是  我做不到  -好吧
- It's everywhere and I can't-- - Okay.
我停不下来  没办法不去想
I can't stop it and I can't keep it out of my head.
好吧  好吧  我相信你  我相信你
Okay, okay, okay. I believe you. I believe you.
西斯科和我说拉姆齐要那些受害者感到恐惧
Cisco told me that Ramsey needs his victims to be scared
才能成功地感染他们
for the infection to take.
是和恐惧有关的氨基酸
Something about a fear-related amino acid.
如果你能感受到这些僵尸的感受呢
What if you're feeling what those zombies are feeling?
他们的恐惧呢
The fear inside them?
不管是什么  让其停止吧
Whatever it is, just make it stop.
塞西尔  你还不明白吗
Cecile, don't you get it?
你就是个僵尸探测器
You're a fricking zombie detector.
只有你才能带我们逃离这里
You're our way out of here.
市中心又发生一起207
We've got another 207 downtown.
各单位请回应
All available units respond.
207是指绑架
207 is an abduction.
过去五分钟内已经发了十起绑架案
There's been ten of those in the last five minutes.
爱瑞丝  我知道你在听
Iris, I know you're listening.
我要见到你
I need to see you.
在我们开始一起生活的地方
Meet me where our life together began--
在你接受我求婚的地方见
where you said yes.
爱瑞丝
Iris--
那不是他
that's not him.
那东西或许听起来像巴里  甚至看起来像他
That might sound like Barry, it might even look like him,
但那是黑暗闪电侠
but that is Dark Flash.
你不能确定
You don't know that.
如果巴里还活在里边呢
What if Barry is still alive in there?
如果是陷阱呢
What if it's a trap, all right?
我们都没有通讯设备  太冒险了
We don't even have comms. It's too risky.
听我说
Listen to me.
我只需要看着他的眼睛
I just need to look him in his eyes.
如果发射器对拉姆齐没用
If the Emitter doesn't work on Ramsey,
我还能回来再试试别的
I get to come back and try something else.
但是如果你跑出去了  而那不是巴里
But if you go out there and that's not Barry,
你可能会被感染或是更糟
you could get infected or worse.
拜托
Please.
"无论生病还是健康"
"In sickness and in health."
爱瑞丝
Iris.
Iris!
巴里
Barry?
是的  爱瑞丝
Yes, Iris?
是我
It's me.
并且不止有我
And so much more.
快点
Come on.
拉姆齐
Ramsey.
这把戏不错吧
Neat little trick, huh?
你现在明白了吧  爱瑞丝
Don't you see now, Iris?
快啊
Come on.
跨纬度外推器
连接完成
我对于
My control over
我血亲兄弟姐妹的控制是绝对的
my Blood Brothers and Sisters is absolute.
随着更多被治愈的灵魂加入我的血脉
As more cured souls accept my lifeblood,
他们都会变成我身体的
they become extensions of one collective body--
延伸
mine.
你要我来  为什么
You asked me here. Why?
为了给你一次机会
To offer you a chance.
巴里会想让你追随他选择的这条道路
Barry would want you to follow him down this path he chose.
不
No.
生命的道路
The path of life.
你不是在拯救生命  拉姆齐
You aren't saving lives, Ramsey.
你在摧毁它的美好
You're destroying what makes one beautiful.
巴里
Barry...
我知道你能听到我  你能听到我对你说
I know you can hear me and you can hear what I tell you--
我爱你
that I love you.
在我们经历过了那么多之后
And after everything that we've been through together...
我知道这不是我们故事的结局
I know that this is not how our story ends.
回到我身边吧
Come home to me.
为什么巴里要回到你身边
Why would Barry come home to you?
你接受了他在危机中的死去是必然
You accepted his death in Crisis as inevitable.
什么样的妻子会愿意埋葬自己的丈夫
What kind of wife is willing to bury her husband?
爱瑞丝  离开那里
Iris, get out of there.
时候未到
In good time.
这还没有结束
This is not over.
相信我  爱瑞丝
Trust me, Iris.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
没事
No.
我收回了外推器的音频
I piggybacked the audio off the extrapolator.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我得再试一次  爱瑞丝
I have to try again. Iris...
他差点杀了你
he almost killed you.
我们不能就这么放弃了  西斯科
We can't just give up, Cisco.
我们没有
We're not.
但如果我们要打败血怒和黑暗闪电侠
But if we're gonna take down Bloodwork and Dark Flash,
我们需要用到光子发射器
we need to do it with the Photon Emitter.
你都没有测试过那东西
You haven't even tested that thing.
我们没时间了
We have no time.
也许你不记得了
Maybe you don't remember,
但是我们其实为这个准备了好几星期
but we actually have been preparing for this for weeks.
不  我们准备的是迎接闪电侠
No, we've been preparing for the Flash to die
为了拯救世界而死  不是毁灭世界
trying to save this world, not--not helping to destroy it.
这不重要  我们反正都要失去他
It doesn't matter! We were gonna lose him anyway!
这就是他要我们做准备迎接的
This is the moment he prepared us for.
我们还有四小时
We still have four hours.
也就是240分钟  我不会让拉姆齐
That is 240 minutes, and I am not letting Ramsey
抢走一分一秒
take a single one of those from me.
我不会放弃巴里  他是我丈夫
I am not giving up on Barry. He's my husband.
他曾是
He was.
他也曾是我最好的朋友
And he was my best friend.
没有人想要放弃谁
And no one's giving up on anybody
因为已经没有什么可以放弃的了
because there is nothing left to give up on.
爱瑞丝  他不在了
Iris, he's gone.
他终究会离开我们
He was always gonna leave us.
不管发射器有没有作用
And whether or not the Emitter works,
都不会改变这一事实
it's not gonna change that.
发射器快好了
The Emitter's almost ready.
当它完成  我就用在血怒身上
And when it is I'm gonna use it on Bloodwork,
然后我会用在黑暗闪电侠身上
and I'm gonna use it on Dark Flash.
乔
Joe!
躺着别动
Just lie still.
离她远点
Get the hell away from her.
阿莱格拉
Allegra!
冰霜  队长还好吗
Frost! Is Captain West okay?
不好
No.
我们得离开这里
We need to get the hell out of here.
走
Let's go.
快回来  快回来
Get right back. Get right back.
没事  没事
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
快跑
Come on!
等下
Oh, wait!
我的天  帮我
Oh, my God. Help me!
我的天
Oh, my God.
这坚持不了多久
That's not gonna hold for very long.
这离尖端科研实验室还有十个街区
S.T.A.R. Labs is still ten blocks away.
十个街区  十个街区
Ten blocks? Ten blocks?
我们能做到  快走
We can do it. Let's go.
站起来  我的血亲兄弟和血亲姐妹
Rise, my Blood Brother and Blood Sister.
你们被治愈了
You are cured.
现在  你们有了不死之身
Now you will never die.
感受灼烧吧  血怒
Feel the burn, Bloodwork!
你就这点本事吗  拉蒙先生
Is that all you've got, Mr. Ramon?
跨维度外推器  连接完成
太可惜了
Too bad.
西斯科
Cisco!
我的生命之血是礼物
My lifeblood is a gift.
你准备好接受它了吗
Are you ready to receive it?
不行
No.
你还还有其他的用途
You have another purpose to serve.
审判日快来了
The reckoning is near.
我的军队就要准备好进军尖端科研实验室了
My army is almost ready to march on S.T.A.R. Labs.
你到底想要尖端科研实验室的什么
What the hell do you want with S.T.A.R. Labs?
粒子加速器
The Particle Accelerator.
你帮忙创造的技术
The very tech you helped to create
将是承载我无上解药的容器
will be the vessel carrying my glorious cure.
很快中城里的所有人都会被赐予永恒的生命
Soon all of Central City will be granted eternal life,
而我选择你  拉蒙先生  来做我的传信人
and I choose you, Mr. Ramon, to be my messenger.
去  告诉你的队友
Go, tell your team
尖端科研实验室的粒子加速器
the great S.T.A.R. Labs Particle Accelerator
已经准备好完成他的真实意义
is ready to fulfill its true purpose.
救赎即将来临
Salvation is nigh.
鞭打屁股即将来临  伙计
An ass-whipping is nigh, pal...
你会输的  拉姆齐
And you're gonna lose, Ramsey.
你会输的
You're gonna lose.
一直勇敢到最后
Plucky right up until the end.
我就知道我选对了人
I knew I picked the right guy.
爱瑞丝
Iris!
如果你在听
If you're listening...
我要回家了
I'm coming home.
你看这个
Look at this.
拉姆齐没撒谎
Ramsey wasn't lying.
巴里侵入了粒子加速器
Barry hacked the Particle Accelerator.
他在为血怒做准备
He was getting it ready for Bloodwork.
那就是他为什么装作巴里
That's why he was pretending to be Barry.
但是为什么
But why?
假如拉姆齐仅仅是
If Ramsey drops even just a tiny amount
往核心里滴几滴血  等它爆炸时
of his blood into the core and it explodes,
传染性细胞就会雾化
the infectious cells will aerosolize
在顷刻间感染整个中城
and it would affect all of Central City in seconds.
你只要一呼吸就会被传染
All you'd have to do is take a breath.
爸
Dad!
做点什么  冰霜
Do something, Frost.
我不能  我应付不了这个
I can't-- I can't handle this.
失血过多  看起来是脾脏破裂
There's a lot of blood loss. Looks like a nicked spleen.
冰霜  我没有我需要的器材
Frost, I don't have the equipment I need
来缝合这个复杂的伤口
to close up this complicated of a wound,
但是你能用你的冰能做到
but you can with your ice powers.
我做不到
I can't.
不  你可以
Yes, you can.
冰霜  拜托
Frost, come on.
在拉尔夫和巴里之后
After Ralph and Barry?
-冰霜  你来控制  -怎么做
- Frost, take control. - How?
让自己感受那份恐惧  数到三
Let yourself feel the fear, count to three,
然后放手去做  因为英雄都是这么做的
and do it anyway, because that's what heroes do.
一  二
One, two...
三
Three.
喜欢吗
You like that?
你喜欢吗
尖端科研实验室
坦白说  我们两个的计划都失败了
For the record, both our plans failed.
是啊
Yeah.
我朝着一个方向  而你朝着另一个方向
I just went in one direction while you went in the other,
而不是一起想出一个计划
instead of figuring out a plan together.
是啊
Yeah.
我本该实现它的
I should've made that happen.
我本该领导小队
I should've led the team.
现在还不晚
It's not too late.
巴里选你是有原因的
Barry chose you for a reason.
别怀疑自己  西斯科
Don't doubt yourself, Cisco.
怎么了
What?
拉姆齐说的话
Something Ramsey said...
"我知道我选择了正确的人"
"I knew I picked the right guy."
巴里也说过这样的话
Barry said those words.
巴里让我做队长的时候
Barry said those exact words to me
也对我说了一模一样的话
when he made me team leader.
拉姆齐本能传染我的
Ramsey could've infected me.
他也能杀了我
He could've killed me.
但他没有  相反他无故大转变
But he didn't-- instead he just did a complete 180 for no reason.
还有其他事情
There's something else.
拉姆齐说  我要回家了
Ramsey said, "I'm coming home."
上次我见巴里的时候请求他回家
I begged Barry to come home the last time I saw him,
但我以为没有起作用
but I didn't think that I was getting through.
爱瑞丝
Iris...
如果那就是巴里呢
what if that was Barry?
如果你是对的
What if you were right
他还存活在黑暗闪电侠中
and he's still alive inside Dark Flash?
那他会告诉我们该怎么做
Then he could be trying to tell us what to do.
我们必须要打败血怒
We gotta take down Bloodwork.
有人在门口
Someone's at the barrier.
我来履行我的使命
I have arrived to fulfill my destiny.
是的  我的军队要来了
And yes, my army is coming.
爱瑞丝
Iris...
西斯科
Cisco...
让光进来
let the light in.
我想我明白了巴里的计划
I think I just figured out Barry's plan...
他刚刚告诉了我们下一步
And he just told us the next step.
我们要关闭防御
We need to lower the defenses.
让他们进来
Let them in.
是时候让死亡终结了
It's time to put an end to death once and for all.
找到拒绝我血液的人  杀死他们
Find the humans who rejected my lifeblood and kill them.
你想让我做什么
You want me to do what?
巴里的计划是让光进来
Barry's plan is to let the light in.
不是让拉姆齐在城市传播他的病
It isn't for Ramsey to spread his infection to the city,
是让你用巨大的紫外线爆炸
it's for you to spread the antidote...
来传播解药
with one hell of a UV blast.
但我做不到
But I can't do that.
别担心  我己经计算好了
Don't worry, I've done all the calculations.
我们会全程指导你
We'll walk you through the whole thing.
现在快去管道里
Just get to the pipeline now.
尖端科研实验室内部通话装置激活
晚上好  闪电侠小组
Good evening, Team Flash.
我不断尝试
I have tried repeatedly
赐给你们永生  但你们都拒绝了
to bestow upon you eternal life, yet you've refused.
所以现在
So now,
与其不断的试图给予你们生命的恩赐
instead of continuing to offer you the gift of life,
我已经命令我的血亲们从你那里夺走
I've ordered my Blood Brothers to take it from you.
现在当你们逃命时
Now as you run for your worthless lives,
请记住  你们的队长  闪电侠
do keep in mind that your leader, Flash,
现在属于我的
belongs to me now.
我有他的接入码  手印和知识
I have his access codes, his handprint, his knowledge.
我的目标一定会实现
My objective will be achieved.
把爱瑞丝和西斯科带来
Bring me Iris and Cisco.
我想让你们知道你们败得有多大
I want you to know the scope of your failure.
我的生命之血正围着加速器转动
My lifeblood is circling the accelerator.
等速度足够快时
And when it gathers enough speed,
它会和内部的能量碰撞
it'll collide with the energy inside
这个碰撞会治愈整座城市
and the resulting collision will cure this city...
还有你
and you.
巴里
Barry...
我相信你
I trust you.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
杀了她
Kill her.
巴里
Barry...
我们是一体的  你和我
We are one, you and I.
挣扎是没用的
It's pointless to fight it.
我知道你想要执行我的意愿
I know you want to execute my will.
我能感到你的内心  闪电侠
I can feel it inside you, Flash.
好多了
Much better.
粒子轨道
准备好逃跑吧
Get ready to run.
你打算做什么
What are you gonna do?
我能做的
What I do.
巴里
Barry?
撞击前我们只剩五个循环
We only have about five rotations left before collision.
撞击周期
每个循环多久
How long is each rotation?
幸运的话几秒钟
A few seconds if we're lucky.
撞击周期
阿莱格拉  你到底在哪
Allegra, where the hell are you?
来了
Right here!
我打开这扇门时
When I open this door,
你使出全力用紫外线攻击这些粒子
you need to hit these particles with all the UV rays you've got.
你可以的  别犹豫
You got this. Don't hold back.
只剩一个循环了
One rotation left!
撞击周期
现在
Now!
巴里
Barry.
是我
It's me.
刚才那个想把我们都杀了的家伙去哪了
where's the scary guy who tried to kill us all?
他跑不远
He won't get far.
没人能拒绝我
I won't be denied!
好  先待在这
Okay, just stay here.
你无法再控制我了
You can't control me anymore.
而且我不会让你再伤害任何人
and I'm not gonna let you hurt anybody else.
我再说最后一次
For the last time...
我要拯救所有人
I am trying to save everyone!
你不明白吗
Don't you understand?
你不是这里的英雄  我才是
You're not the hero here, I am!
西斯科  你在吗
Cisco, you with me?
永远都在
Always.
巴贝尔协议解除了  通信系统也恢复了
Babel's been lifted, comms are up.
我们回来了
We are back.
我们有什么可以关得住拉姆齐的地方吗
What do we have that can hold Ramsey?
米切·罗梅罗的事之后
After Mitch Romero,
我们知道管道牢房不管用
we know a pipeline cell won't work.
精神增强室
The M.A.C.
它包含切斯特的黑洞能量
It contained Chester's black hole energy.
所以关住拉姆齐应该易如反掌
So Ramsey should be a walk in the park.
闪电侠  你没事吧
Flash, you okay?
退后
Stay down!
死前有什么遗言想说吗
Any last words before your death?
我只想好好享受剩下的时光
I just want to enjoy the time I have left.
我也这么想
I felt the same way.
我的好孩子
My beautiful boy...
拉姆齐
Ramsey.
你都干了什么
What have you done?
儿子
My son...
我太想你了
I've missed you so much.
妈妈
Mom?
这怎么可能
How is this even possible?
我带她来的
I brought her.
你进入我的思想
You entered my mind
为了揭示我隐藏在心底的疑虑
to bring out that doubt that was hidden inside.
我让你感染我
I left you infect me
这样我可以回报你  揭示你心底的疑虑
so I could return the favor and bring out yours.
不可能
Impossible.
我没有疑虑  只有信念
I have no doubt. Only conviction.
拉姆齐
Ramsey.
如果妈妈能多陪我一天
I would give anything to
我愿意付出任何代价
have just one more day with my mom.
你现在也有这样的机会
You have that chance right now.
听她的话
Listen to her.
他说得对
He's right.
你天生是拯救生命的
You were born to heal.
但你却成了毁灭天使
But you've become an angel of destruction.
不
No.
这没有真的发生
This isn't happening.
这不是真的
This isn't real.
亲爱的儿子
My dear son...
你当初那么急切地想救我
You wanted so desperately to save me.
现在就让我来拯救你吧
Now let me save you from yourself.
我只是想帮助所有人
I just wanted to help them all.
不
No!
也许她错了
Perhaps she was wrong.
我天生就是要拯救世界的
I was born to save the world!
而且我还有这个能力
And I still can.
你能听到我说话吗  闪电侠
Can you hear me, Flash?
我是被选中来拯救世界的人
I was chosen to save the world.
我挣脱这些锁链时  就会完成我的宿命
And when I escape these chains, I will complete my destiny.
你们都会接受我的治疗
And you will all accept my cure.
囚禁协议支撑住了
Containment protocol's holding.
它起效了
It worked.
我们做到了  我们打败他了
We did it. We beat him.
是时候开始下一场战斗了
Now it's time for our next fight.
莱拉说拉姆齐正式被天眼会羁押了
Lyla says Ramsey is officially in A.R.G.U.S. Custody.
而且我给本地几家医院打了电话
And I called the local hospitals--
看来拉姆齐感染没有长期影响
Ramsey's infection doesn't seem to have any long-lasting effects.
所以大家都会没事吗
So everyone's gonna be okay?
除拉姆齐之外的所有人  冰霜做了些检测
Everyone except Ramsay. Frost ran some tests,
看来他的情况
and it looks like his condition is, um...
挺永久的
pretty permanent.
乔在休息室休养
Joe's resting in the lounge,
我觉得我应该去看看他
and I think I am gonna go check on him.
成为黑暗闪电侠是什么感觉
What was it like being Dark Flash?
我知道发生了什么  但我却无法阻止
I knew what was happening, but I couldn't stop it.
说实话  我用尽了全力
Honestly, it took everything I had
才没让我伤害你们
just to keep from hurting you guys.
但随着时间持续  我知道我...
But as the night went on, I could tell I was--
我在接近他  我能感觉到
I was getting to him. I could feel him
他对自己的怀疑越来越深
doubting himself more and more.
谢谢你所做的一切
Thank you for what you did.
你拯救了这个城市
You saved the city.
彼此彼此
Right back at ya.
但你真的应该感谢冰霜  是她带我过来的
But you should really thank Frost. She got me there.
她真是太厉害了
She's badass.
没错  她是
Yeah, she is.
说到这里  冰雪女王在哪
Speaking of, where is the Ice Queen?
凯特琳  我知道这几天
Caity, I know the last couple of days
就像在坐过山车一样
have been a roller-coaster,
但是我想谢谢你相信我
but I just wanted to say thanks for believing in me
即便连我都不相信自己
even though I didn't believe in myself.
不用谢
No thanks needed.
不管怎样
And for it's worth,
我为你在这几个月里的成长感到骄傲
I'm really proud of how you've grown these last few months.
我等不及想看你接下来会怎样
I can't wait to see where you go next.
我也是
Me, too.
但是今晚  我想你应该出来
But for tonight, I think you should take over.
你应该和你的团队在一起
It's only right that you're with the team
面对即将到来的危机
for whatever Crisis is about to bring.
各位
Guys?
我不想沉默地坐着
Sitting in silence really isn't how I want to spend
度过接下来的几分钟
the next few minutes.
乔
Joe...
你把手表给我的时候  这意味着
when you gave me your watch, that meant...
对我来说意味着整个世界
that meant the world to me.
我想把我的手表给你
I wanna give you mine.
这样我就知道  无论我在哪里
So I know wherever I go,
我的一部分都和你在一起
part of me is with you.
我很爱你这一点
I love you for that.
但是你现在哪里也不会去
But you're not going anywhere yet.
所以你先拿着
So you hold on to it.
好
All right.
HR·威尔斯曾经对我说
H.R. Wells told me once...
“巴里·艾伦的超能力不是速度“
"Barry Allen's superpower isn't speed.
”而是希望”
"It's hope.
“是希望  那个孩子心中充满了希望”
It's hope, and that kid has an endless reservoir of it."
巴里  直到我真正了解你
I didn't know how right he was
才知道他说得有多正确
until I really got to know you, Barry.
无论将要发生什么
Whatever is about to happen,
这个世界都因为有你而更美好
this world's a better place for having you in it.
你刚出现在我生活中的时候
You know, when you first came into my life,
我几乎对一切都失去了信心
I had lost faith in just about everything.
你拯救了我  巴里
You saved my life, Barry.
天啊  我想起了以前的日子
God, I remember the old days.
没有二重身
No doppelgangers,
没有闪点  没有时间旅行
no Flashpoint, no time travel.
只有我们对抗坏人
It was just us against the bad guys.
我怀念那段时间
I miss that.
我不知道  我挺喜欢时间旅行
I don't know, I kinda like time travel.
你被困在神速力的时候
When you were stuck in the Speed Force,
我会让西斯科用震波送我去滨水区
I would have Cisco vibe me to the Waterfront
看我们的初吻
so I could watch our first kiss.
就是你为了拯救世界
You know, the one you had to erase from the timeline
从时间线上抹掉的那个
to save the world.
你为什么要这样做
Why'd you do that?
我不知道  也许当你沉浸在悲伤里时
I don't know. I guess when you're filled with sadness,
是那些快乐的回忆支撑你度过那段时间
happy thoughts are what get you through the day.
有什么能比与你的一生挚爱
And what's happier than getting half your first kiss
分享初吻更幸福呢
with the love of your life
唯有经历两次
other than getting to do it twice?
我们的爱情永远不会结束  巴里
Our love story never ends, Barry.
危机到来也不会结束
Not even with Crisis.
爱瑞丝  这是无法避免的
Iris, it's inevitable.
也许吧
Maybe.
但无论你会消失  或者
But whether you vanish or...
或者更糟  我都会陪着你
or worse, I am gonna be there with you.
我会陪着你  直到最后  好吗
I'm gonna be right there with you to the very end, okay?
因为除了危机
Because the only thing
我更确定会发生的  就是我们
more inevitable than Crisis is us.
爱瑞丝说得对
Iris is right.
无论会发生什么
Whatever's in store for us,
都无法改变我们对于彼此的意义
they can't change what we mean to each other.
不会消除我们心中的回忆
Can't erase what's in our hearts.
只要我们记住这一点
As long as we hold on to that...
我们就已经在危机发生前打败它了
we've beaten Crisis before it even begins.
《闪电侠》
这么多年来  我周游世界
For so many years, I've traveled across worlds,
2019年12月9日  下午11:58
穿越多元宇宙  只为了做一件事
across the multiverse, to do one thing.
杀了你
Kill you.
但是现在  我们在这里
And now here...
你救了我的命
you saved my life.
服从并重新开始你的生活
Submit and begin your life anew.
展现给我看
Show me.
知识就在你心中
The knowledge is within you.
未完待续
无限地球危机